# **Kevin Hartwig**

## (541) 517-5693 | <u>kevinhartwig@gmail.com</u>

### **Summary**

Driven goal-oriented technology leader with over 20 years of progressive experience in software and site reliability engineering. Excels in taking ownership and leading project from inception through release. Passion for implementing and driving observability and incident management best practices. Effective communicator to stakeholders of all levels of seniority and experience.

#### Languages

Java, C#, C/C++, Bash, Python, Ruby

## **Technologies and Tools**

AWS, Terraform, Kubernetes, Github Actions, Datadog/New Relic, Splunk/Sumologic, PagerDuty, Docker, Jira. Postgres

## **Operating Systems**

macOS, Windows, Unix (Linux, AIX)

#### **PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE**

Hinge Health | Portland, OR

Staff Site Reliability Engineer | March 2022 - May 2024

## Senior Site Reliability Engineer | February 2020 - March 2022

- Led cloud migration initiative from PaaS provider (Aptible) to AWS.
- Designed AWS organizations and security architecture to conform to AWS best practices.
- Established incident committee to drive incident management improvements company wide including parterning with engineering leadership to design and implement a company incident management process, develop and run incident management training, build out of monitoring and alerting integrations between observability platforms and PagerDuty.
- Led project to redact PHI data from service logs enabling offshore employees to support production.
- Led multiple observability projects including onboarding of SumoLogic and migration from New Relic to Datadog.
- Built organizational AWS IAM strategy using Google Workspace, AWS SSO and Terraform.
- Partnered with engineering, security, compliance on defining and implementing infrastructure to support organizational initiatives.
- Collaborated with engineering leadership to define and document best practices related to operational excellence including code freezes, on-call expectations, scheduled maintenance, PHI logging standards.
- Expanded SRE team from 2 engineers to 7 including hiring of management and Director of Infrastructure.
- Provided 24/7 hour on-call support to meet 99.9% uptime SLA's.

#### Senior DevOps Engineer | August 2019 - February 2020

## DevOps Engineer | June 2018 - August 2019

- Led project to automate deployment of service level alerting through New Relic at service build time.
- Built out infrastructure monitoring and alerting solution using New Relic Infrastructure.
- Created Python tool to export and import Rundeck jobs to support deployment to multiple environments.
- Developed and maintained service and infrastructure deployment tooling implemented in Bash, Python, CloudFormation and Ansible.
- Created tooling to deploy new Splunk Indexers and implemented hot/cold storage strategy to reduce costs.
- Maintained and updated infrastructure built in AWS utilizing EC2, ECS, RDS and other technologies.
- Partnered with Product, Account Management and Engineering teams to plan and deploy new features and ensure customer needs are met.
- Led ticket grooming and daily stand up meetings.
- Provided 24 hour on-call support on a rotational basis.

## XPO Logistics (Formerly Con-way Enterprise Services) | Portland, OR

## Principal Software Engineer | June 2014 - June 2018

- Led project to migrate document repository of 750 million documents from local optical storage to Amazon S3 storage.
- Designed and developed a solution to migrate all documents in our company's contract management solution (Filenet), into our document management system.
- Led project to modernize internal SOAP web services to secure restful web services.
- Led project to migrate existing VB6 applications and common libraries to C#.
- Consulted with process analysts and management to design, prioritize and cost projects.
- Consulted with business partners on integration and best practices for using the document management system.
- Evaluated and implemented various third-party libraries used in document processing, including document scanning, image manipulation/compression, and barcode recognition.
- Integrated standard and custom TWAIN functions into existing document scanning software.
- Developed scripts and automation tools to assist in the deployment of applications.
- Provided high level support to internal business partners, external vendors and customers.
- Trained and mentored junior developers.

#### Con-way Enterprise Services | Portland, OR

#### Senior Software Engineer | September 2011 - June 2014

## Sofware Engineer | January 2008 - September 2011

• Designed and developed multiple SOAP web services, which communicate with internal C applications and databases using IPC, HTTP/WebDAV and JDBC.

- Developed application to automatically detect and redact sensitive customer information from delivery manifest documents utilizing OCR and barcode recognition software.
- Created a custom benefits workflow solution, which allows users to classify and review employee documents related to the yearly open-enrollment process.
- Evaluated and integrated third-party barcode recognition software into an existing software framework.
- Updated existing VB6, .NET and Java applications and their installation packages to be Windows 7 and Windows XP compliant.
- Developed Java application to update document indexing information triggered off of an XML request received from a Tibco messaging service (JMS).
- Developed C application to start and continuously monitor unix applications status based on configuration information stored in a DB2 database.
- Collaborated in the design and development of a Java build script template utilizing Ant.
- Tested and supported high volume document scanners and cameras used as imaging devices.

## Department of Defense - Naval Undersea Warfare Center | Keyport, WA

## Software Developer | June 2006 - January 2008

- Worked as a part of a team to develop, test, and support the United States Navy's Carrier Vessel Tactical Support Center (CV-TSC) and Undersea Warfare Decision Support System (USW-DSS).
- Designed and developed Java application to simulate the deployment of sonobuoys to be used in testing and readiness activities.
- Performed on-site installations of the USW-DSS software.
- Provided on-site, phone and email support to customers and other support personnel.
- Performed validation testing of both software and hardware components for deployment and readiness exercises.

## **EDUCATION**

#### **B.S. Computer Science, Minor in Business Administration**

\*Oregon State University - Corvallis, Oregon